[{"question":"1.Delaying noncritical activities to lower peak demand on resources is known as resource\nA.Shifting\nB.Effectiveness\nC.Manipulating\nD.Resource smoothing\nE.Allocation","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"D.","help":"If resources are adequate but the demand varies widely over the life of the project, it may be desirable to evenout resource demand by delaying noncritical activities (using slack) to lower peak demand and, thus, increaseresource utilization. This process is called resource smoothing.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"2.If resources are not adequate to meet peak demands, the resulting reschedule is termed\nA.Resource-constrained scheduling\nB.Time-constrained scheduling\nC.Mandatory leveling\nD.Project resource adjustment\nE.Allocation","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"A.","help":"If resources are not adequate to meet peak demands, the late start of some activities must be delayed, and theduration of the project may be increased. This process is called resource-constrained scheduling.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"3.Which of the following is a potential consequence of failing to schedule limited resources?\nA.Costly activity delays\nB.Costly project delays\nC.Difficulty in taking quick corrective action\nD.Both A and B are correct\nE.A, B, and C are all correct","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"E.","help":"The consequences of failing to schedule limited resources are a costly activity and project delays usually manifestthemselves midway in the project when quick corrective action is difficult.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"4.When developing a new software package, the software must be designed, the code must be written, and the codemust be tested. This is an example of a ______ constraint.\nA.Physical\nB.Technical\nC.Resource\nD.Schedule\nE.Time","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"B.","help":"A network for a new software project could place the activities in the network, as a sequence of (1) design,(2) code, and (3) test. In other words, you cannot logically perform activity 2 until 1 is completed, andso on. The project network depicts technical constraints.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"5.Which of the following is not one of the types of project constraints?\nA.Physical\nB.Technical\nC.Resource\nD.Time\nE.All of these are types of project constraints","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"D.","help":"If resources are not adequate to meet peak demands, the late start of some activities must be delayed, and theduration of the project may be increased. The absence or shortage of resources can drastically alter technicalconstraints. In rare situations, physical factors cause activities that would normally occur in parallelto be constrained by contractual or environmental conditions.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"6.Sam the project engineer has been scheduled to run the product system test at the same time he is to build amarketing prototype. This is an example of a ______ constraint.\nA.Physical\nB.Technical\nC.Resource\nD.Scheduling\nE.Time","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"If one person must perform all activities, the resource constraint requires the activities be performed in sequenceor series.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"7.Susan is to conduct environmental testing but the chamber cannot hold all the equipment that she wants to test.This is an example of a _________ constraint.\nA.Physical\nB.Technical\nC.Resource\nD.Scheduling\nE.Time","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"A.","help":"Since space allows only one person to work at one time, all tasks have to be performed sequentially this is aphysical constraint.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"8.All of the following are kinds of resource constraints except\nA.Materials\nB.People\nC.Equipment\nD.Information\nE.All of the above are resource constraints","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"D.","help":"See list on pages 255-257.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"9.Sam is trying to order the concrete needed to continue his project. However, the supplier won't be able to deliverit until next week. This is an example of a _______ constraint.\nA.Working capital\nB.People\nC.Equipment\nD.Information\nE.Materials","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"E.","help":"Material availability and shortages have been blamed for the delay of many projects. When it is known that alack of availability of materials is important and probable, materials should be included in the projectnetwork plan and schedule.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"10.A special truck that George needs on his project has been scheduled on another project. This is a ______ constraint.\nA.Working capital\nB.People\nC.Equipment\nD.Information\nE.Materials","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"Equipment is usually presented by type, size, and quantity. In some cases equipment can be interchanged to improveschedules, but this is not typical. Equipment is often overlooked as a constraint. The most common oversightis to assume the resource pool is more than adequate for the project.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"11.Most of the scheduling methods available today require the project manager to classify the project as either_______ constrained or ______ constrained.\nA.Time, quality\nB.Quality, resource\nC.Cost, time\nD.Quality, cost\nE.Time, resource","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"E.","help":"Most of the scheduling methods available today require the project manager to classify the project as eithertime constrained or resource constrained.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"12.Regina's boss has told her that her project is very important. If the critical path is delayed, she will be givenwhatever she needs to get it back on schedule. Her project is ________ constrained.\nA.Time\nB.Quality\nC.Cost\nD.Performance\nE.Resource","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"A.","help":"A time-constrained project is one that must be completed by an imposed date. If required, resources can be addedto ensure the project is completed by a specific date. Although time is the critical factor, resource usageshould be no more than is necessary and sufficient.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"13.In reviewing the status of her project with top management, Shirley was told that there only were two programmersthat she could use for her project. Her project is __________ constrained.\nA.Time\nB.Quality\nC.Cost\nD.Performance\nE.Resource","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"E.","help":"A resource-constrained project is one that assumes the level of resources available cannot be exceeded. If theresources are inadequate, it will be acceptable to delay the project, but as little as possible.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"14.All resource leveling techniques involve\nA.Delaying noncritical activities\nB.Delaying critical activities\nC.Using negative slack\nD.Both A and C are correct\nE.A, B, and C are all correct","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"A.","help":"All leveling techniques delay noncritical activities by using positive slack to reduce peak demand and fill inthe valleys for the resources.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"15.Scheduling time-constrained projects focuses on resource\nA.Demands\nB.Increases\nC.Assumptions\nD.Utilization\nE.All are correct","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"D.","help":"Scheduling time-constrained projects focuses on resource utilization.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"16.The most widely used approach to apply heuristics, which have been found to consistently minimize project delayover a large variety of projects is the\nA.Parallel method\nB.Resource method\nC.Materials\nD.Both A and C are correct\nE.A, B, and C are all correct","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"A.","help":"The parallel method is the most widely used approach to apply heuristics, which have been found to consistentlyminimize project delay over a large variety of projects.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"17.Resource leveling can provide\nA.Lower peak demand\nB.Reduced resource need over the life of the project\nC.Reduced fluctuations in resource demand\nD.Both A and B are correct\nE.A, B, and C are all correct","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"E.","help":"Practitioners have attacked the utilization problem using resource leveling techniques that balance or smoothdemand for a resource. Basically, all leveling techniques delay noncritical activities by using positiveslack to reduce peak demand and fill in the valleys for the resources.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"18.Jan is trying to reallocate resources in a time-constrained project to create smoother resource utilization witha low level of risk. She should move to activities with the\nA.Smallest duration\nB.Least slack\nC.Most slack\nD.Lowest identification number\nE.Highest cost","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"C.","help":"The rationale is those activities with the most slack pose the least risk.","difficulty":"Level: Difficult"},{"question":"19.In a resource-constrained project, which of the following is most likely to be changed?\nA.The completion date\nB.The budget\nC.Project quality\nD.Both A and B are equally likely\nE.A, B, and C are all equally likely","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"A.","help":"Managers who fail to schedule resources usually encounter a scheduling risk when it is too late to work aroundproblems, resulting in a project delay.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"20.In a resource-constrained project, the first priority in assigning resources is usually given to activities withthe\nA.Smallest duration\nB.Least slack\nC.Most slack\nD.Lowest identification number\nE.Highest cost","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"B.","help":"The first activity placed in the schedule would be the activity with the least slack (rule 1).","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"21.In a resource-constrained project the second priority in assigning resources is usually given to activities withthe\nA.Smallest duration\nB.Least slack\nC.Most slack\nD.Lowest identification number\nE.Highest cost","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"A.","help":"If all activities have the same slack, the next rule would be invoked (rule 2), and the activity with the smallestduration would be placed in the schedule first.","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"22.The word Heuristics means\nA.Resource constraints\nB.Flexibility\nC.The critical path changed\nD.Parallel activities become sequential\nE.Rule of thumb\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: ComprehensionLearning Objective: Resource Allocation MethodsLevel: Medium","type":"multipleChoice","answer":"E.","help":"A.More people working on the same activityB.There are possible startup and shutdown costsC.A resource may be moved from one activity to another and then backD.Both B and C are correctE.A, B, and C are all correct","difficulty":"E.A, B, and C are all correct"},{"question":"A planner splits the continuous work included in an activity by interrupting the work and sending the resourceto another activity for a period of time and then having the resource resume work on the original activity.Splitting can be a useful tool if the work involved does not include large start-up or shutdown costs—forexample, moving equipment from one activity location to another. The most common error is to interrupt \"peoplework,\" where there are high conceptual start-up and shutdown costs.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: ComprehensionLearning Objective: Splitting ActivitiesLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"24.The U.S. Forest Service \"snapshot from practice\" illustrated the importance ofA.Time constraintsB.Resource constraintsC.Cost constraintsD.Both B and C are correctE.A, B, and C are all correct","difficulty":"E.A, B, and C are all correct"},{"question":"It is important to remember that, if resources are truly limited and activity time estimates are accurate, theresource-constrained schedule will materialize as the project is implemented—not the time-constrained schedule!Therefore, failure to schedule limited resources can lead to serious problems for a project manager. Thebenefit of creating this schedule before the project begins leaves time for considering reasonable alternatives.\nAACSB: Analytic\nBloom's: ComprehensionLearning Objective: Benefits of Scheduling ResourcesLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"25.More common problems associated with managing multiproject resources include all of the following exceptA.Inefficient resource utilizationB.Delays in one project cause delays in other projectsC.Reducing \"downtime\" created by lack of tasks to performD.Resource bottlenecksE.All of these are common problems","difficulty":"E.All of these are common problems"},{"question":"See List on page 274\nAACSB: Analytic\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Multiproject Resource SchedulesLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"26.When a company will reduce the number of projects they have to manage internally to only core projects and sendnoncritical projects to contractors and consulting firms this is calledA.OutsourcingB.Redistribution of projectsC.Project allocationD.Task sharingE.Both B and D are correct","difficulty":"E.Both B and D are correct"},{"question":"Many companies are using outsourcing as a means for dealing with their resource allocation problems. In somecases, a company will reduce the number of projects they have to manage internally to only core projectsand outsource noncritical projects to contractors and consulting firms. In other cases, specific segmentsof projects are outsourced to overcome resource deficiencies and scheduling problems.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: ComprehensionLearning Objective: Multiproject Resource SchedulesLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"27.Which of the following is not one of the more common problems associated with scheduling multiproject resources?A.Overall schedule slippageB.Inefficient resource utilizationC.Resource bottlenecksD.Both A and C are correctE.A, B, and C are all correct","difficulty":"E.A, B, and C are all correct"},{"question":"See List on Page 274.\nAACSB: Analytic\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Multiproject Resource SchedulesLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"28.In a resource-constrained project the third priority in assigning resources is usually given to activities withtheA.Smallest durationB.Least slackC.Most slackD.Lowest identification numberE.Highest cost","difficulty":"E.Highest cost"},{"question":"In very rare cases, when all eligible activities have the same slack and the same duration, the tie is brokenby the lowest activity identification number (rule 3), since each activity has a unique ID number.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: ComprehensionLearning Objective: Resource Allocation MethodsLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"29.In the Botanical Garden example, which of the following was used to solve the resource problem?A.Resource allocationB.Smoothing resource demandC.The parallel methodD.Both A and C are correctE.A, B, and C are all correct","difficulty":"E.A, B, and C are all correct"},{"question":"The Botanical Garden project schedule reached the three goals of smoothing: The peak of demand for the resourcewas reduced, resources over the life of the project have been reduced, the fluctuations in resource demandwere minimized.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Resource Allocation MethodsLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"30.Project budgets are developed by time-phasing which of the following?A.Resource schedulesB.Work packagesC.The network diagramD.Both A and C are correctE.A, B, and C are all correct","difficulty":"E.A, B, and C are all correct"},{"question":"Using your project schedule, you can time-phase work packages and assign them to their respective scheduled activitiesto develop a budget schedule over the life of your project.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: ComprehensionLearning Objective: Using the Resource Schedule to Develop a Project Cost BaselineLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"31.A project budget report is showing our project as spending $35,000 against a budgeted amount of $40,000. Whichof the following is true?A.We are spending less than we should for the projectB.We are doing a good job managing the projectC.We should check to see if all the bills have been paidD.Both A and B are correctE.We can't be sure how the project is going","difficulty":"E.We can't be sure how the project is going"},{"question":"There is no way to be certain how much of the physical work has been accomplished.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: ComprehensionLearning Objective: Using the Resource Schedule to Develop a Project Cost BaselineLevel: MediumFill in the Blank Questions","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"32.Delaying noncritical activities to lower peak demand and, thus, increase resource utilization is called _______leveling.resource","difficulty":"resource"},{"question":"Practitioners have attacked the utilization problem using resource leveling techniques that balance or smoothdemand for a resource. Basically, all leveling techniques delay noncritical activities by using positiveslack to reduce peak demand and fill in the valleys for the resources.\nAACSB: Analytic\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Types of Resource ConstraintsLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"33.A(n) ________ constraint addresses the sequence in which project activities must occur.technical or logic","difficulty":"technical or logic"},{"question":"The start and sequence of activities has been based solely on technical or logical considerations. For example,a project network for framing a house might show three activities in a sequence: (1) pour foundation, (2)build frame, and (3) cover roof.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Overview of the Resource Scheduling ProblemLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"34.Having one person responsible for performing several activities, all due at the same time, is an example of a(n)________ constraint.resource","difficulty":"resource"},{"question":"If one person must perform all activities, the resource constraint requires the activities be performed in sequenceor series.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: ComprehensionLearning Objective: Overview of the Resource Scheduling ProblemLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"35.Trying to renovate a ship compartment that is too small for more than one person is an example of a(n) ________constraint.physical","difficulty":"physical"},{"question":"In rare situations, physical factors cause activities that would normally occur in parallel to be constrainedby contractual or environmental conditions. For example, in theory the renovation of a sailboat compartmentmight involve four to five tasks that can be done independently. However, since space allows only one personto work at one time, all tasks have to be performed sequentially.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Types of Resource ConstraintsLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"36.A shortage of programmers to write software is an example of a(n) ________ type of resource constraint.people","difficulty":"people"},{"question":"This is the most obvious and important project resource. Human resources are usually classified by the skillsthey bring to the project—for example, programmer, mechanical engineer, welder, inspector, marketing director,supervisor. In rare cases some skills are interchangeable, but usually with a loss of productivity. The manydiffering skills of human resources add to the complexity of scheduling projects.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Types of Resource ConstraintsLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"37.The shortage of computer chips to produce a circuit board is an example of a(n) ________ type of resource constraint.materials","difficulty":"materials"},{"question":"Material availability and shortages have been blamed for the delay of many projects. When it is known that alack of availability of materials is important and probable, materials should be included in the projectnetwork plan and schedule.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Types of Resource ConstraintsLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"38.If three copiers are needed to produce a final report on time and only two are available, the project is facinga(n) ________ type of resource constraint.equipment","difficulty":"equipment"},{"question":"The most common oversight is to assume the resource pool is more than adequate for the project.\nAACSB: Analytic\nBloom's: ComprehensionLearning Objective: Types of Resource ConstraintsLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"39.Hector wants to bring on another programmer to work on the project but the company does not have anyone who hasthe needed skills. Hector's project is facing a(n) ________ constraint.people type of resource","difficulty":"people type of resource"},{"question":"This is the most obvious and important project resource. Human resources are usually classified by the skillsthey bring to the project—for example, programmer, mechanical engineer, welder, inspector, marketing director,supervisor. In rare cases some skills are interchangeable, but usually with a loss of productivity. The manydiffering skills of human resources add to the complexity of scheduling projects.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Types of Resource ConstraintsLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"40.In order that the new product is on the shelf for the Christmas buying season, the development of the new productwould be classified as a(n) ________ constrained project.time","difficulty":"time"},{"question":"A time-constrained project is one that must be completed by an imposed date. If required, resources can be addedto ensure the project is completed by a specific date. Although time is the critical factor, resource usageshould be no more than is necessary and sufficient.\nAACSB: Analytic\nBloom's: ComprehensionLearning Objective: Classification of a Scheduling ProblemLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"41.Beth has two engineers assigned to her project and cannot get any more even if it means slipping the due dateon her project. She is managing a(n) ________ constrained project.resource","difficulty":"resource"},{"question":"A resource-constrained project is one that assumes the level of resources available cannot be exceeded. If theresources are inadequate, it will be acceptable to delay the project, but as little as possible.\nAACSB: Analytic\nBloom's: ComprehensionLearning Objective: Classification of a Scheduling ProblemLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"42.All leveling techniques delay noncritical activities by using ________ to reduce peak demand.positive slack","difficulty":"positive slack"},{"question":"All leveling techniques delay noncritical activities by using positive slack to reduce peak demand and fill inthe valleys for the resources.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Resource Allocation MethodsLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"43.Scheduling activities in a constrained project typically has ________ as the top heuristic rule.minimum slack","difficulty":"minimum slack"},{"question":"See list on Page 260.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Resource Allocation MethodsLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"44.The ________ is the most widely used approach to apply heuristic rules to scheduling activities in a constrainedproject.parallel method","difficulty":"parallel method"},{"question":"The parallel method is the most widely used approach to apply heuristics, which have been found to consistentlyminimize project delay over a large variety of projects.\nAACSB: Analytic\nBloom's: ComprehensionLearning Objective: Resource Allocation MethodsLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"45.When using the ________ scheduling technique, the work in an activity is interrupted to work on another activityand is then resumed at a later point in time.splitting or multitasking","difficulty":"splitting or multitasking"},{"question":"A planner splits the continuous work included in an activity by interrupting the work and sending the resourceto another activity for a period of time and then having the resource resume work on the original activity.\nAACSB: Analytic\nBloom's: ComprehensionLearning Objective: Splitting ActivitiesLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"46.In scheduling resource-constrained projects, _________ are typically used rather than optimum mathematical solutions.heuristics","difficulty":"heuristics"},{"question":"A few researchers have demonstrated optimum mathematical solutions to the resource allocation problem but onlyfor small networks and very few resource types. The massive data requirements for larger problems make puremathematical solutions (e.g., linear programming) impractical. An alternative approach to the problem hasbeen the use of heuristics (rules of thumb) to solve large combinatorial problems.\nAACSB: Analytic\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Resource Allocation MethodsLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"47.In scheduling terms, ________ constrained means that project duration is fixed and resources are flexible.time","difficulty":"time"},{"question":"In scheduling terms, time constrained means time (project duration) is fixed and resources are flexible.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Classification of a Scheduling ProblemLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"48.In scheduling terms, ________ constrained means that a specific resource is fixed and the duration of the projectis flexible.resource","difficulty":"resource"},{"question":"In scheduling terms, constrained means resources are fixed and time is flexible.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: ComprehensionLearning Objective: Classification of a Scheduling ProblemLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"49.Start-up and shutdown costs are major considerations when using the ________________ scheduling technique.splitting/multitasking","difficulty":"splitting/multitasking"},{"question":"The most common error is to interrupt \"people work,\" where there are high conceptual start-up and shutdown costs.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Splitting ActivitiesLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"50.To deal with problems related to having several concurrent projects, companies are creating ________ to overseethe scheduling of resources across multiple projects.project offices or project departments","difficulty":"project offices or project departments"},{"question":"More and more companies create project offices or departments to oversee the scheduling of resources across multipleprojects.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: ComprehensionLearning Objective: Multiproject Resource SchedulesLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"51.Many companies are using ________ from contractors and consultants as a means of dealing with the peaks and valleysof resource allocation among projects.outsourcing","difficulty":"outsourcing"},{"question":"Many companies are using outsourcing as a means for dealing with their resource allocation problems. In somecases, a company will reduce the number of projects they have to manage internally to only core projectsand outsource noncritical projects to contractors and consulting firms. In other cases, specific segmentsof projects are outsourced to overcome resource deficiencies and scheduling problems.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: ComprehensionLearning Objective: Multiproject Resource SchedulesLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"52.The ______________ is the most widely used approach to apply heuristics in resource-constrained projects.parallel method","difficulty":"parallel method"},{"question":"The parallel method is the most widely used approach to apply heuristics, which have been found to consistentlyminimize project delay over a large variety of projects.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Resource Allocation MethodsLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"53.The ability to more efficiently manage the ebbs and flows of project work is one of the major driving forcesbehind ____________ today.outsourcing","difficulty":"outsourcing"},{"question":"The ability to more efficiently manage the ebbs and flows of project work is one of the major driving forcesbehind outsourcing today.\nAACSB: Analytic\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Multiproject Resource SchedulesLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"54.Without a time-phased __________ good project schedule and cost control are impossible.budget","difficulty":"budget"},{"question":"These systems do not measure how much work was accomplished for the money spent! Hence, without time-phasingcost to match your project schedule, it is impossible to have reliable information for control purposes.\nAACSB: Analytic\nBloom's: ComprehensionLearning Objective: Using the Resource Schedule to Develop a Project Cost BaselineLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"55.A project cost baseline is also called __________.planned value (PV)","difficulty":"planned value (PV)"},{"question":"The outcome of these budget allocations is the project cost baseline (also called planned value—PV), which isused to determine cost and schedule variances as the project is implemented.\nAACSB: Analytic\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Using the Resource Schedule to Develop a Project Cost BaselineLevel: MediumTrue / False Questions","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"56.The sequence of (1) pour foundation, (2) build frame, and (3) cover roof is a type of physical constraint.FALSE","difficulty":"FALSE"},{"question":"The start and sequence of activities has been based solely on technical or logical considerations. For example,a project network for framing a house might show three activities in a sequence: (1) pour foundation, (2)build frame, and (3) cover roof.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Overview of the Resource Scheduling ProblemLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"57.Too many parallel activities for one individual are an example of a resource constraint.TRUE","difficulty":"TRUE"},{"question":"If one person must perform all activities, the resource constraint requires the activities be performed in sequenceor series.\nAACSB: Analytic\nBloom's: ComprehensionLearning Objective: Overview of the Resource Scheduling ProblemLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"58.A project that is not resource-constrained is time-constrained.TRUE","difficulty":"TRUE"},{"question":"In scheduling terms, time constrained means time (project duration) is fixed and resources are flexible, whereconstrained means resources are fixed and time is flexible.\nAACSB: Analytic\nBloom's: ComprehensionLearning Objective: Classification of a Scheduling ProblemLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"59.Resource leveling is only used on projects which are resource-constrained.FALSE","difficulty":"FALSE"},{"question":"Practitioners have attacked the utilization problem using resource leveling techniques that balance or smoothdemand for a resource. Basically, all leveling techniques delay noncritical activities by using positiveslack to reduce peak demand and fill in the valleys for the resources.\nAACSB: Analytic\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Resource Allocation MethodsLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"60.Resource Bottlenecks are one of the three more common problems encountered in managing multiproject resourceschedules.TRUE","difficulty":"TRUE"},{"question":"See list on Page 274.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Multiproject Resource SchedulesLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"61.The inability to get more than two earth movers on a construction site at the same time is an example of a physicalconstraint.TRUE","difficulty":"TRUE"},{"question":"In rare situations, physical factors cause activities that would normally occur in parallel to be constrainedby contractual or environmental conditions.\nAACSB: Analytic\nBloom's: ComprehensionLearning Objective: Types of Resource ConstraintsLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"62.The most obvious and important kind of resource constraint is a lack of materials.FALSE","difficulty":"FALSE"},{"question":"People are the most obvious and important project resource.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Types of Resource ConstraintsLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"63.Having too few programmers and too many engineers is an example of a people resource constraint.TRUE","difficulty":"TRUE"},{"question":"Finding people with certain differing skills adds to the complexity of scheduling projects.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Types of Resource ConstraintsLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"64.If a project needs one earth-mover six months from now and the organization has four such machines, there isno equipment resource constraint.FALSE","difficulty":"FALSE"},{"question":"The most common oversight is to assume the resource pool is more than adequate for the project. For example,if a project needs one earth-moving tractor six months from now and the organization owns four, it is commonto assume the resource will not delay the pending project. However, when the earthmoving tractor is due on-sitein six months, all four machines in the pool might be occupied on other projects.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Types of Resource ConstraintsLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"65.A lack of readily available engineers is a technical constraint.FALSE","difficulty":"FALSE"},{"question":"When the number of people and/or equipment is not adequate to meet peak demand requirements and it is impossibleto obtain more, the project manager faces a resource-constrained problem.\nAACSB: Analytic\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Resource Allocation MethodsLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"66.All projects are usually either time-constrained or resource-constrained.TRUE","difficulty":"TRUE"},{"question":"Most of the scheduling methods available today require the project manager to classify the project as eithertime constrained or resource constrained.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Classification of a Scheduling ProblemLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"67.To determine if a project is time-constrained or resource-constrained you would consult the project prioritymatrix.TRUE","difficulty":"TRUE"},{"question":"Project managers need to consult their priority matrix to determine which case fits their project.\nAACSB: Analytic\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Classification of a Scheduling ProblemLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"68.Scheduling time-constrained projects focuses on the optimal utilization of resources.TRUE","difficulty":"TRUE"},{"question":"A time-constrained project is one that must be completed by an imposed date. If required, resources can be addedto ensure the project is completed by a specific date. Although time is the critical factor, resource usageshould be no more than is necessary and sufficient.\nAACSB: Analytic\nBloom's: Reflective ThinkingLearning Objective: Classification of a Scheduling ProblemLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"69.All leveling techniques delay noncritical activities by using positive slack to smooth out the resource requirements.TRUE","difficulty":"TRUE"},{"question":"All leveling techniques delay noncritical activities by using positive slack to reduce peak demand and fill inthe valleys for the resources.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Resource Allocation MethodsLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"70.Scheduling time-constrained projects focuses on resource utilization.FALSE","difficulty":"FALSE"},{"question":"Scheduling time-constrained projects focuses on resource utilization.\nAACSB: Analytic\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Resource Allocation MethodsLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"71.Scheduling resource-constrained projects focuses on completing the project as soon as possible under the givenconstraints.TRUE","difficulty":"TRUE"},{"question":"When the number of people and/or equipment is not adequate to meet peak demand requirements and it is impossibleto obtain more, the project manager faces a resource-constrained problem. Something has to give. The trickis to prioritize and allocate resources to minimize project delay without exceeding the resource limit oraltering the technical network relationships.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Resource Allocation MethodsLevel: Difficult","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"72.Heuristics are used in resource-constrained projects to develop the optimal schedule.FALSE","difficulty":"FALSE"},{"question":"Heuristics do not always yield an optimal schedule, but they are very capable of yielding a \"good\" schedule forvery complex networks with many types of resources.\nAACSB: Analytic\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Resource Allocation MethodsLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"73.The top priority in using heuristics to allocate scare resources is those activities with the smallest duration.FALSE","difficulty":"FALSE"},{"question":"Heuristics allocate resources to activities to minimize project delay; that is, heuristics prioritize which activitiesare allocated resources and which activities are delayed when resources are not adequate.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Resource Allocation MethodsLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"74.The critical path in a resource-constrained schedule can be a group of disjointed, unconnected activities.TRUE","difficulty":"TRUE"},{"question":"The traditional critical path concept of sequential activities from the start to the end of the project is nolonger meaningful. The resource constraints can break the sequence and leave the network with a set of disjointedcritical activities.\nAACSB: Analytic\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Computer Demonstration of Resource-Constrained SchedulingLevel: Medium","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"75.Splitting is a scheduling technique used to get a better schedule or better resource utilization.TRUE","difficulty":"TRUE"},{"question":"Splitting tasks is a scheduling technique used to get a better project schedule and/or to increase resource utilization.\nAACSB: Reflective Thinking\nBloom's: KnowledgeLearning Objective: Splitting ActivitiesLevel: Easy","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"76.Without a time-phased budget good project schedule and cost control are impossible.TRUE","difficulty":"Level: Easy"},{"question":"77.Many companies are using outsourcing as a means for dealing with their resource allocation problems associatedwith managing multiproject resources.","type":"boolean","answer":"TRUE","help":"Companies may hire temporary workers to expedite certain activities that are falling behind schedule or contractproject work during peak periods when there are insufficient internal resources to meet the demands of allprojects.Short Answer Questions","difficulty":"Short Answer Questions"},{"question":"78.Identify and briefly describe the three types of project constraints.","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. Technical (logic); the sequence that activities must be performed, 2. resource; the absence of required people,materials, equipment, or working capital, and 3. physical; limitations based on space or environmental limits.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"79.What is the difference in project goals when using resource leveling on time-constrained projects and using iton resource-constrained projects?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"In time-constrained projects the goal is to smooth out the peaks and valleys and thus improve the utilization.In resource-constrained projects the goal is to achieve the shortest project duration given a limited supplyof resources.","difficulty":"Level: Difficult"},{"question":"80.Identify the potential impacts of project constraints.","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. reduction in slack on the project network, 2. decrease in flexibility, 3. possible decrease in parallel activities,and 4. increase in the likelihood of delaying the project.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"81.Identify and give an example of the three types of resource constraints.","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. People; by skill classification (engineer, programmer, salesperson), 2. materials; paint, data, parts, and3. equipment; computers, earth-movers, office space.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"82.Identify and briefly describe the two classifications of scheduling problems.","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. time-constrained; the end date is fixed and needed resources are available, 2. resource-constrained; the resourcesare fixed and the end date is flexible.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"83.What are the disadvantages of resource leveling?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. loss of flexibility, 2. increased risk of project delay, 3. more critical or near critical activities.","difficulty":"Level: Difficult"},{"question":"84.Why would a project manager use heuristics rather than a mathematical solution to level resources?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"Mathematical models work on small networks and a small number of resources. Larger projects have massive datarequirements. Heuristics tend to yield a good solution without the heavy burden imposed by math models.","difficulty":"Level: Difficult"},{"question":"85.What are the three most common heuristics (in order of priority) used to allocate resources to project activities?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. minimum slack; start with activities with the least amount of slack, 2. smallest duration; if two activitieshave the same slack select the one with the smallest duration, and 3. lowest activity identification number,if slack and duration are the same select the earliest activity.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"86.Describe the parallel method for applying heuristics to the allocation of project resources.","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"The first priority is to allocate resources to the activity with the least amount of slack, usually an activityon the critical path. If more than one activity has the same amount of slack then selects the activity withthe smallest duration. If more than one activity has the same slack and the same duration then select theactivity that occurs the earliest.","difficulty":"Level: Difficult"},{"question":"87.Why should project managers be cautious about using the splitting scheduling technique?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"The splitting technique is where an activity is interrupted and the resources are applied to another activity.The potential problems are in the addition of shutdown and startup costs which are added as one moves fromactivity to activity prior to completing the original activity.","difficulty":"Level: Medium"},{"question":"88.Identify and briefly discuss the three more common problems encountered in managing multiproject resource schedules.","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. overall schedule slippage, 2. inefficient resource utilization, and 3. resource bottlenecks.","difficulty":"Level: Difficult"},{"question":"89.Identify and briefly describe the potential impacts of resource-constrained scheduling.","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"1. reduced slack reduces flexibility, 2. increased number of critical and near-critical activities, 3. increasecomplexity due to resource constrains added to technical constraints, 4. the critical path may become a setof disjointed critical activities, and 5. formerly critical activities may now become non-critical.","difficulty":"Level: Difficult"},{"question":"90.If your project has spent $50,000 versus a budget of $45,000 and it is a week ahead of schedule, is it a certaintythat your project is doing well?","type":"shortAnswer","answer":"","help":"Not necessarily. You need more information to draw that conclusion.8-1","difficulty":"1"}]